HealthPulse AI, 11 MCP tools, one healthcare platform.
First question to the agent,
show me quality anomalies in California hospitals.
Behind this chat, HealthPulse isn't an app,
it's a Model Context Protocol server.
11 healthcare intelligence tools that any MCP client,
Claude Desktop, Prompt Opinion, the Anthropic API,
a custom agent, can invoke by name.
Right now, Claude is calling the quality monitor tool
against 233,000 rows of real CMS data,
computing Z-scores across all 5,400 U.S. hospitals.
No dashboards, no thresholds, structured output,
a host model can reason over.
And here's the finding, UCI Health Los Alamitos,
48% higher hip and knee readmissions than expected.
Oroville and Kaweah Health flagged as repeat offenders,
not threshold alerts.
Statistical pattern detection across an entire state
in a single tool call.
Next query, what's the equity disparity in Texas?
The equity detector tool is now correlating
every Texas hospital star rating
against the CDC Social Vulnerability Index,
county by county.
Same primitive, different tool.
A Dallas County paradox, vulnerable communities
receiving two-star care while UT Southwestern
next door runs four-star.
Systemic disparity, one tool call.
The executive briefing tool aggregates state data
into a board-ready analysis.
California, 378 facilities, 3.01 average stars,
253 care gaps, 30 high-risk counties.
Claude is now composing the narrative,
findings, anomalies, equity recommendations,
all from a single structured tool call.
PDF export ships built in.
This is agent composability in action.
Layer two, a Next.js dashboard on top of the same tools
for humans.
National view, 5426 hospitals, 3.08 average,
450 quality flags.
Filter to California and the same analysis refocuses
instantly, every facility is searchable.
Type UCSF, five hospitals in the system,
medical center rating a perfect five stars
across CMS quality measures.
Compare any two facilities head-to-head.
UCSF versus Cleveland Clinic, death rates,
safety scores, ED wait times,
all aligned in one LLM readable view.
The equity page visualizes the disparity the tool computes.
0.77 stars, 1,700 high-SVI facilities,
11 tools, real data, zero PHI, built for Agents Assemble.